I have failed my way into success. That
was Rahul Pande. I had gotten offers
from all the big tech companies, Google,
Facebook, and Microsoft. He's a software
engineer who went from almost getting
fired through an acquisition. And they
told me and said, "Hey, we are going to
get acquired by you're going to do a
full round of interviews next Monday to
getting promoted to staff at Meta in his
20s." I interviewed him so that we could
learn from that experience. The thing I
wish I realized way way earlier in my
career is that and he was very honest
with his entire career story. I came in
with like this attitude of like okay I
should be like one of the best engineers
and then getting rejected for the same
promotion twice was a real setback. What
portion of your career growth do you
think was luck?
The beginning of your career is unusual.
you went to Stanford but you joined a
startup immediately and it looks like uh
a very small startup. What's the story
behind you joining a startup right out
of college? The story is in my fifth
year at Stanford I was at the school for
5 years doing an undergrad and master's
degree. I met in that fifth year. One of
the reasons I actually decided to stick
around for that fifth year is because I
felt like I hadn't really made any
faculty connections and Stanford just
like any other top institution is famous
in part because of amazing instructors
and faculty who were doing
groundbreaking research. And I felt like
what a shame if I leave this institution
and not really understand or take part
in that. And so the fifth year I was a
RA like a research assistant in a lab
with a professor named Yuri Lusco who
was like a rising star and I thought
this is a cool opportunity and that led
to a lot of the work we were doing in
the lab. He decided to spin it out into
a company and Stanford actually is
pretty well known for being fairly
generous or willing to allow their
faculty to go out and do companies and
like have this revolving door with
academia. And so when that happened, I
felt like it was almost too good of a
story to pass up. Like I could be one of
10 or 20,000 engineers in big tech if I
go join Google or Microsoft or Meta. And
I I had received offers at all of them.
But then I felt like, okay, this is a
story where I had this connection
relationship with the professor. He
trusts me. I trust him. And it just
feels like a Silicon Valley unique story
that will it could go really really well
in which case amazing or worst case it's
a good story to tell. Yeah. Yeah. And so
I felt like there was not an hour to use
and that's kind of why I ended up
choosing that route. Makes sense. And
you're early in your career so if it
fell flat you didn't have a whole lot of
responsibility. How many people were
were in that early venture? Yeah. Yeah.
So there was a professor. He had one
industry veteran who had been around the
block and so it was like two founders
and then there was one other person in
the lab with me. So two new grads me and
him and there was one more person. So I
think I had joined technically aside
from the two founders as like employee
number two. So very very early on into
the company's formation. Right. How did
you think about risk at that point?
Because I think a lot of people they're
evaluating big tech and and versus
startups and big tech is kind of the you
know the high expected value path and
then startups are kind of you know boom
or bust type of path. So did you think
about that at all or was it a no-brainer
to go to the startup? Yeah, I did think
about that. I think the couple things I
thought about is one way door versus
two-way door. Like let me try it out and
startups. Most things in your career are
two-way doors in the sense that you try
it out, you learn something, you
experiment, and then you can always back
out. You can always decide to leave the
startup and then go to big tech if
needed. So that was one consideration.
And the other consideration too, if I'm
being honest, is that I felt like I had
attained that level of success or that
level of like approval from big tech.
And if I hadn't had that, I honestly am
not sure if I would have done the
startup. But what I mean by that is like
I had done an internship the prior
summer at Facebook, right? Now known as
Meta in 2013. And then after that
internship, I had gotten offers from all
big tech companies. I gotten five offers
including what I mentioned like Google,
Facebook and Microsoft, Twitter and
Square. So five companies in total. And
so that gave me a lot of confidence that
okay I I can do it right I can hopefully
with some preparation I'm hopeful or
confident in my ability to go back and
get that opportunity. So there wasn't it
didn't feel like that much of a risk
right whereas if I had never gotten that
big tech offer I think I might have
really thought twice well let me go get
a stable job which is going to be much
more kind of of a known commodity to
other companies so that if and when I
decide to move on from my first gig I
can get a really good job on my second
gig. But because I already had that
insurance policy of Stanford on my
resume along with these other offers, I
felt like I could be a lot more risk on
that early in my career. Right. Right.
That makes sense. So when you went into
the actual startup itself, would you say
that it was a good outcome from the
acquisition or was that kind of like a
you know aqua hire maybe not the best
outcome you're hoping for? Yeah, more
the latter for sure. I think the thing
with acquisition but I learned that
acquisition is probably one of the most
overloaded terms in Silicon Valley. What
do you mean? Like you could talk about
acquisition as in like the most famous
might be or one of the most famous might
be like WhatsApp getting acquired by
Facebook for 19 billion. Right. Right.
In 2014 that's like an acquisition and
like everyone became filthy. Right.
Right. Then you also have acquisitions
or frankly the total opposite which is
the company effectively failed. Yeah.
And they're calling an acquisition to
save the dignity of the founders. Um, I
think what happened with Postay, the
company I joined, it was somewhere in
the middle. It was like a little bit, if
I'm being honest, closer to the failure
end, I mean, I probably shouldn't call
it a failure. It was basically like an
opportunistic bet that okay, the startup
that I joined, like I mentioned, it was
spun out of academic work, right? And so
I think the bet that we were making is
that hey we have interesting IP
intellectual property. We have some
interesting ideas that are more
academic, but there's not really a clear
pathway to generating revenue or
building a product, right? And so when
the startup acquisition offer came
along, like Pinterest, this hot company,
which already had 100 million users,
when they came along, it's hey, pairing
your technology and your technology
knowhow with our core product and PMF
product market fit that we already have,
that could really create something where
1 plus 1 equals three. That I think was
uh a really attractive proposition and
so I think that it we never gave the
company a chance to really fail like it
just ended within like eight months of
formation right and so I think to answer
your question directly I think uh
financially it wasn't like an Fri
outcome like I'm never have to work
again it certainly wasn't that I
basically you can kind of think of it as
me entering in Pinterest with a slightly
higher package than what a normal new
grad at Pinterest would have received So
certainly, I mean, you can't complain.
Like I feel like I learned a lot about
Silicon Valley. I learned a lot about
acquisitions, and I came in with like a
financially better outcome, but it
wasn't like a life-changing amount of
money. Got it. Got it. Yeah. And I think
one more thing I'll say, which I think
is really often overlooked is that
storytelling and the story that you tell
yourself and the story you tell other
people, the narrative that you can
create about what you did, why you did
it, and why it's interesting. That is
incredibly powerful. Right. And I think
honestly more than anything else I feel
like me being able to tell this story of
how I was a enterprising young engineer
22 year 22 years old and I took a bet on
a startup and I did this crazy story.
Honestly I get a lot of mileage out of
that story. Like I mean genuinely I get
like I learned a lot but also just like
being able to tell that story and
explain to people what happened, what I
learned from it that actually has a ton
of value. And so one of the things I
tell people on taro or just in general
when I mentor people is that if you have
a choice between A and B and you feel
like A is the one which will give you
exposure to more unique opportunity,
unique people, unique stories, that's a
really good argument to pick option A
because it just will broaden your
perspective and give you that
storytelling ability. So looking back on
that, let's say I was a new grad and I
think there's a lot in the audience.
would you recommend that they pick this
same opportunity if they had the the
same decision to make? Yeah, I think it
depends. So, a couple things that made
this story unique and why I felt like it
was the right decision for me at the
time was number one, I had a lot of
social proof on my resume already. Like
I went to Stanford, I had done
internship at Facebook, which is already
a huge company at that point. And I felt
like the founder of a startup was one of
the best people in the field in the
world. Right. Right. like undoubtedly
this person knew more about
recommendation systems and big data and
you know we didn't call it machine
learning back then but effectively
machine learning back then so it's like
clearly uh a really good person to just
be around and and see how they operate
and so I think if those things are true
then yeah I mean I would encourage
anyone who's that early on in their
career go do the crazy risky thing which
might fail but I will say that's
honestly more of the exception than the
norm so if you're a normal like if you
are the typical path, which is what I
would describe as like you went to a
pretty good school and you got a degree
and you are like struggling to find your
first job. Actually, I would recommend
go and find the biggest brand name you
can like the biggest company like
reputable company and go work there
because I do think there's so much value
in just acrewing credibility. Right.
Right. Like go work at Amazon. Go I
think your first job was Amazon, right?
Like that's a great first gig. Like go
work at Amazon. go work at Google if you
can get in. I think that will set you up
well at a baseline for whatever else you
want to do later on your career. And if
you have this exceptional opportunity
and you're able to justify it by like an
amazing founder and you already have
some of that kind of backup plan because
of your background, I think then it
makes sense. But for the most part, I
would just recommend the standard path
is probably the best because it's a
standard like that is it's a standard
for a reason, right? So like probably
the gend path is what I'd recommend for
most people. Yeah. Yeah, I agree with
that. I think you know big tech versus
startups comes up a lot and one of the
big things about going directly into a
big brand is instant step change in your
credibility. You just immediately you
have some prestige on your resume. Yeah.
there's a lot of value and just even if
you just went to big tech for like a
year or two and then you left and even
if your end goal was to go to startups I
kind of feel like developing the
engineering fundamentals while
collecting that stamp is one of the
highest EV things that you could do
knowing now your your situation that
makes sense you had an extraordinary
opportunity and you already had the the
stamps essentially Stanford
uh Facebook you're kind of already in
there so that makes sense you got
acquired by Pinterest and So you're kind
of uh it was a pretty big company at the
time, right? Pinterest is maybe a growth
stage startup at the time. Yeah, around
400 people. Well, 400 people. Okay. So
it was bigger than a a true startup
startup, but it was still much smaller
than big tech. You know, when you got
acquired, what was that like? Yeah, I
think in the end I was happy with it,
but I will tell you like it was very
chaotic and very stressful in the
process to get there because like
basically the way it worked right the
behind the scenes is that it was like my
professor and this other industry
veteran and they were like much much
more senior than me and the other new
grad who joined CO together and like you
know they had 20 years or more
experience clearly they were much more
wellconed much more in the know and so
the way it worked is that I came into
work at Kos the startup one day and they
told me and said hey we are going to get
acquired by Pinterest. They want to
interview everyone on the team. You're
going to do a full round of interviews
next Monday, which was like a couple
days away. And so that was like a a big
change in the company strategy, right?
Obviously, I was like, we're really
shutting down. We're going to get
acquired. And then the last 48 hours,
the next like 72 hours or whatever was
extremely stressful because I had, you
know, I was like out of interview prep
for almost a year at that point. And as
you know, you can talk about this later,
but like interview prep is a very
different skill compared to actually
doing the engineering job. And so I was
very worried that I wouldn't actually
get the offer at Pinterest because I
didn't do well in the interview. And in
fact, that almost came true. Like I
remember I did the full round like they
took everyone basically immediately to
the final round interview. Um so I had
like five or six interviews in one day
and they I was borderline. They called
me back in to the SF office again to
say, "Hey, like we know we still had
some doubts or like we had some
questions follow up for you." And I did
two more interviews and luckily I nailed
those. Like I did really well on those
and then I got the offer. But like I was
very worried because like there was a
tech crunch article and there was like a
big news announcement about how
Pinterest has acquired this hot
technology company and it would have
sucked if I if it was like oh I joined
the startup but I didn't actually take
part in the acquisition and all my
friends would have texted me or messaged
me and like oh congratulations and I'm
like ah well I got nothing out of it
because I didn't get an offer. So it
kind of worked out in the end but it
really was pretty stressful process and
it was rushed right. Had you vested any
uh options in your in Cos at the time or
Okay. So you would have gotten nothing
because CO had only been around for
about eight months at that point, right?
Okay. So if you didn't pass that, you
would have gotten fired essentially and
had gotten no upside from any equity
after that. That's right. Yeah. And so
like literally like when I after that on
this whole like on-site interview, I was
feeling pretty nervous. So then I like
messaged back my old recruiters at other
big tech companies I get offers from and
like start hey like are you still hiring
or can I join cuz I was worried that
that would be a backup let me go back to
Google let me go back to Facebook right
luckily it worked out and then I wanted
to be part of that story and I I knew
the people at COA so I wanted to kind of
join with them so that was like a nice
transition but yeah that was like it
would have been effectively start from
scratch and become like a new grad all
over right was that leak code to to just
a standard algo the interview loop.
Yeah, that was a pretty standard like I
think it was, you know, uh, leak code.
They asked me like what I did on the
startup, what projects I worked on.
Yeah, I know it's like one behavioral
interview, I think, and then a bunch of
we code, man. Okay. You'd have a very
different story if you failed that.
Not nearly as good. Um, so, okay, so you
get into Pinterest. What was the what
was that like? Did they have a ladder
system at that time? Did you get plugged
into a certain level um in terms of
career side of things? Yeah, they they
they had just developed a engineering
leveling system and I came in at L3
which is like their entry level
engineer. So effectively they borrowed
it from Google and Facebook. So L3 is
entry level, L4 is mid-le, L5 is senior.
So I came in at L3 and then I
transitioned away from recommendation
systems or like data engineering which
is effectively what I was doing at the
startup and I transitioned into mobile
development. And so I kind of did a
career reset in some ways by joining
Pinterest and then that led to kind of a
longer ramp up time and I actually ended
up getting rejected for promotion which
we can talk about if that if that's
interesting. Yeah. But yeah, I basically
came in at the L3. I see. So um you
mentioned that you were working in a
different space. How did you choose what
you were working on at Pinterest and
also maybe you can tell us a little more
about what you were working on too.
Yeah, I mean uh the way they put you
into teams is they actually modeled it
off of Facebook. So Facebook has a thing
called boot camp. At least they did back
in the day where it was like a six week
program where you like learn about
engineering fundamentals and you pick a
team. They had something called base
camp is a d like a a play on that. And
the idea of base camp is that it's like
a bridged version like two or three
weeks where you learn about different
teams at Pinterest and you decide what
to go work on. By going through the base
camp process and talking to a bunch of
teams, I kind of made the call that I
didn't want to do things that were more
backend. I wanted to be closer to the
product. I wanted to actually be able to
build something which I could deploy
either at Pinterest or on my own.
Actually, one of the criteria for me is
I wanted to be able to build things on
my own end to end like side projects. I
felt like I wasn't able to properly do
that with my background in like
recommendation systems which I had kind
of built up an expertise in at Stanford
and at CO. You wanted to do that because
uh you had aspirations to start a
company someday. Yeah, I mean I think
vaguely I did have some aspirations like
I think at Stanford like everyone has a
vague aspiration to start a company. So
I there was some element of like yeah I
want to just at some point do the
entrepreneurial thing. I think there's
also just like a more fundamental itch
of like I want to build something and I
felt like you can obviously build things
on the back end too. Like I I did want
to be an owner of the actual user
experience as well. That was important
to me. I just like I wanted to dabble. I
wanted to build things. The idea of
being able to have my name on an app in
the Play Store, like the Android app
store, that was really compelling. And
like my whole family was on Android, so
I could like go home and show them
here's this app I built and like
thousands of people could use it. some
that was like really compelling to me,
right? And so I felt like if I could
just learn Android professionally at
Pinterest with really good people that
could help accelerate my side project
endeavors because that was not an option
at Kosa. There was no such thing as a
mobile team. Like we were only like
three, four people total, right? So I
just wanted to leverage the benefit of a
bigger company to be able to like double
dip and do well professionally hopefully
and also be able to do things on the
side that I thought were interesting.
That made sense. When you actually went
through with it and you you ended up on
this client side uh uh team, did you
learn what you wanted to learn or were
you surprised that it wasn't what you
were expecting? Yeah, I think I did end
up learning what I wanted to learn. Like
there was a really good staff level
andor engineer who got hired a couple
months after me. I learned a lot from
him. Like that was a huge kind of pivot
I would say in my career. Like I was
able to just get a ton of mentorship.
But I will say for the first few months
it was kind of rough. I didn't know how
to properly learn. I had not learned how
to properly learn at that point in my
career. And so Android, especially at at
a somewhat mature company where we had,
you know, I think hundreds of thousands
of lines in the Android app at that
point already. It was not a small code
base. I think I really did struggle like
as someone who had never done Android
professionally before. The first few
months of transitioning were really
difficult for me. And I think I like
that that's kind of the reason why I
think I didn't do well when I initially
went up for promotion at Pinterest is
that I was very slow to ramp up and I
felt like I like read a lot of
documentation. I read a lot of code but
I didn't actually modify I didn't write
much Android code in the first few
months and that was that was rough but I
think eventually I got to the point
where I felt comfortable. So what was
the key change that took you from not
landing code and not being effective in
your onboarding to learning how to learn
and being effective? Yeah, I think a lot
of it honestly was just being surrounded
by really good people. In particular,
this like L6 staff level engineer who
had come from Facebook who joined
Pinterest like I think that person
really like we start to to pair program
and that was I think a really big change
in how I approached the work and I think
just in general like having a team where
you're accountable to something. I think
I did work pretty hard. So like it's not
like I was fooling around and I didn't
know anything. I was spending a lot of
time and I think when you have a team of
people who are like kind of holding you
accountable or they're going to judge
you which is really what was happening I
think that was a really good fire under
my butt to actually learn it properly
and eventually it kind of clicked with
the combination of mentorship and just
enough time in the role. Got it. So for
people who are looking to join a a team,
they're making a similar decision of
like what team to join. Maybe they
already passed interviews. What do you
think is the most important thing in
picking a good team? Yeah, I would say
maybe two things. One is the people part
of it again is like the amount that you
learn is going to be dominated by who
you interact with and like what kind of
discussion or interaction you have with
them. And then the second thing I would
say is how important is that team to the
company. So one of the reasons actually
additional reason why I picked Android
at Pinterest is that one of the big
initiatives for Pinterest in 2015 when I
was working there was international
growth and you're trying to grow a
consumer app
internationally the number one way you
do that the key is going to be Android
is dominant outside of the US and so I
knew that the company would allocate a
lot of smart people a lot of resources a
lot of money frankly into that domain
and I felt like if you're adjacent into
or operating in an area of high growth,
you will inevitably see some of that
growth too, right? So, I think the
combination of those two people and
where the company is growing, I think
matters a lot in team selection. Common
advice I see is a rising tide lifts all
boats. I've seen some people's careers
where they they went from, you know, new
grad to director in five years because
they were working on the one of the most
important things for the company and
they were really delivering. So the
impact was insane and typically career
growth's proportional to your your
impact. So going into the career growth
side of things, you came in as a as a
L3. You you mentioned that you had a
failed promotion. Can you talk me
through how you eventually got the promo
and maybe the story behind what you were
talking about there? Yeah, I mean it's a
pretty difficult journey, honestly. So I
got I got the failed promotion. I got
the feedback. I think honestly that was
probably legitimate. I think it was a
year after I was at Pinterest and I
wanted to go off a promo and it got
rejected and it was like valid feedback.
Okay, you've only been doing Android
professionally for like you know nine
months at that point and you haven't
really added you haven't really banned
that much. That was fair. I went up
again six months later and I got
rejected for the promotion again. So
that was truly demoralizing because I I
came into Pinterest with like this
attitude of like okay I came in through
an aqua hire an acquisition and I should
be like on top of the world. I should be
like one of the best engineers and then
getting rejected for the same promotion
twice was a real
um setback. So luckily what happened in
the second time is I they had like an
appeal process at at Pinterest. So then
I was able to work with a manager to
appeal the promotion and I got I
actually ended up getting it. So Oh,
interesting. That was valuable. One of
the takeaways I learned in that second
time is a big feedback for me for the
rejection was that oh on one of the
projects that you listed in your
promotion packet, you said that you've
been working on it for like 16 months
and they the promotion committee this
anonymous promotion committee
interpreted that to mean that I wasn't
working with urgency or with
deliberation enough and that was like
not true. like in the frame like I think
the framing of it had that framing
because they kind of interpreted this
like long duration of the project. But
then when I clarified that with my
manager and they were able to like uh
kind of advocate for me or put up a
appeal, it it ended up working out. But
I think that kind of showed me the value
of like you really need to be clear
about what you think you're saying. It
may not always be interpreted that way.
And so especially for things like career
growth or like a one-on-one document or
a promotion document, you have to really
be clear about get it reviewed by people
who have been around the block and like
understand like be open to feedback on
how things might be interpreted
differently because you want to avoid
the situation that I ended up in. Yeah,
it's it's interesting. You talked about
duration of the project and how it being
longer hurt you because I've heard the
opposite as well. If you have a a
project that is longer, it's perceived
as larger scope potentially and
therefore maybe a bigger undertaking.
And so I've heard some people say
actually sometimes it can be
advantageous for a project to be longer
durations. Of course, there's no um
one-sizefits-all thing here. It's all
about the context and how the story is
actually told. The color behind it
matters a lot. Yeah. And this is why I
think like you have to be really clear
with your manager about what narrative,
what story are you trying to tell,
right? You have to make sure that you're
aligned with them on that and also
ideally get feedback from other like
tech leads or other people who are in
positions of influence because the same
project if you've been working on for 16
months, it could be really impressive.
Or if it's like this minor experiment
that people assume should have taken you
three months, but you've been working on
for 16 months, that could be held
against you, right? So I think the devil
is in details and you have to be really
like you I I guess like the the learning
I had is that you can't make assumptions
about how you are going to be evaluated
or judged right based off of your own
interpretation. Like software
engineering is like social endeavor like
you have to be able to work with other
people and figure out how are they
judging you? What do they think are your
areas for improvement? And make sure you
figure that out ahead of time so you're
not surprised during a performance
review. One of the last things I want to
go over for this this u leg of your
career is usually from L3 to L4 it's all
about engineering fundamentals and
technical growth and you mentioned a
little bit that having a really strong
mentor was one of the key things that
helped you level up here in terms of
your skills. Was there anything else
that you did that helped you you know
have a lot more impact or really develop
those skills quickly going from three to
four? I think one of the things I
learned from this mentor which was also
incredibly valuable for me when I was
doing my own side projects or like
publishing apps was this willingness to
just operate outside of the codebase.
Like for example I mentioned how the
Pros codebase even though it was still
relatively early it was already quite
mature like compilation like building
the Android app and deploying to the
phone it took I think sometimes between
two and five minutes like it took a long
time to actually do all this
compilation. So it was like a very slow
and painful debug cycle. One of the
things that the mentor showed me is that
hey, you can actually create your own
like mini Android app and make changes
and like copy over themes as needed, but
then you can have this sandbox
environment where the debug cycle is way
faster, right? And I think that was
really eye opening for me cuz it it felt
like making a new app that's like so
much work. It's like this big ambiguous
thing. I don't know how to do that,
right? But when you actually get into
it, it turns out it's not that hard and
it will actually meaningfully increase
your velocity and that fear I had I
think of like being able to dabble and
like break things and you know copy
paste code and modify it over here and
see what happens. I think that went away
after a while and which is also like of
course very valuable for a side project
because you don't have training wheels
you don't have any code to already
modify for a side project right so it
was very valuable for that and I think
that change of attitude of like just
being able to go in and make things and
break things honestly was probably the
biggest mindset shift that led to the
L34 promotion. Yeah, I think a lot of
that promotion too is about contributing
more code and having one of the most
important things for that is like a very
fast iteration loop. So, okay, you you
got the promo at Pinterest and I believe
at this point you you left to Meta. Is
that correct? Yeah, I left in mid 2017.
Got it. What made you want to leave
Pinterest for Meta? I a couple things.
One is I think Meta was a much much
bigger company and I felt like frankly
the engineering brand of Meta was still
quite a bit stronger just in terms of
like name brand and being a huge company
and it was value in that they were
paying more and I felt like in terms of
immediate growth at Pinterest I didn't
see a clear pathway to okay like here's
how my career is going to rocket ship
from from where I am now. And so the
combination of those three led me to
Okay, let me look around and see if I
can get a meaningful bump in my career
promotion or compensation. I do think in
general early on in career, job hopping
is more effective at that. Later on in
career, job hopping is actually
counterproductive.
Oh, what makes you say that job
hopping's counterproductive later in
career? And as you go up the career
ladder, most of your impact is going to
be derived through the influence you
have on other people rather than
actually just coding all day every day.
It is it is rare for like for example a
staff or principal engineer to just
crank out so much code that it justifies
their impact at the company. Usually
what's going to be happening is you're
creating frameworks or tools or systems
that allow other developers to do
productive work. And so for that kind of
work, you need to be in a company long
enough that you have those relationships
and that trust built out. If you are a
like staff or principal engineer, it's
very hard to job hop your way beyond
that. You have just kind of build out
that trust and relationship and then you
get promoted. Whereas early on in career
as long as you show the competency of
hey I can write high quality Android
code I can write highquality production
code that's that might be enough
actually for a company to bring you in
at a higher level or at least a higher
compensation. I think that aligns with
my experience as well. I think my my
promotion from senior to staff I think
was unusually quick because I had a lot
of relationships already. A lot of my
peers had switched companies like very
very fast but I'd stayed in one place
one team for a long time. So actually
that leg came a lot of it was from
influence and people trusting me and
knowing I could get a job done at a
staff level and giving me those
opportunities which I was lucky to
receive. But yeah staying at some place
for a long time gave me more
opportunities for influence and and that
kind of luck. One thing I want to ask
you about cuz you mentioned one thing
about Meta was uh like more social
proof, more prestige. Your resume was
already pretty loaded at the time in
terms of and Pinterest is not a bad
brand. You had Stanford. Um you had
already been at at Meta. So do you feel
like there was additional value in
another stamp or was it more for the the
other aspects of it? Yeah, that's a good
point. I do think part of it was like I
still felt Meta as a much bigger like
everyone in the world had heard of Meta
or at that point it was Facebook
everyone had heard of Facebook not
everyone had heard of Pinterest so part
of it was maybe like this ego of like
it's a more well-known brand both for
the common public and also in terms of
engineering but I think you're right
that that was not the highest order bit
of what I was optimizing for because
like I had already technically had the
Facebook name on my resume I had already
had these other somewhat well-known
names on in my resume. I think it was
more I think focused on this feels like
a place where I can grow my
career a lot faster at Facebook compared
to where I was. When you switched from
Pinterest to Meta, what were the
cultural differences that immediately
jumped out to you? I'll start off by
saying I think they were actually kind
of similar. Like a lot of the Pinterest
culture was influenced by a lot of ex ex
Facebook and ex Google people. So it was
similar in that sense, but Facebook
culture was my internship and from
people who had joined Pinterest from
Facebook. And you could tell at Facebook
was like the authentic like taste of it
had gotten but on steroids. So for
example like at Pinterest I remember the
culture was every code review every
change would be reviewed by at least two
people and they would actually have
these thing called herald roles where if
you modified a particular part of the
codebase it would automatically add
reviewers and they were blocking
reviewers so you couldn't land the code
until they took a look. At Facebook as
you probably know like it's actually
very rare for that to happen. Usually
all you need is one accept, one LGTM,
one green check mark and you can land
it. And so I was actually kind of
shocked at wait people are just landing
code that quickly without all the other
like checks and balances. So then that
was one big difference. I think people
were more direct at Facebook. at
Pinterest. One of the common criticisms
of the company was that it was kind of
too nice, which is kind of a weird
criticism, but like I think what they
meant to say was that people weren't
saying the difficult thing around
feedback or prioritization and then
therefore projects or people who had no
business actually staying at the
company, they stuck around a lot longer.
M whereas at Facebook I think they were
actually quite I I don't want to say
like they were more mean but they were
definitely a lot more direct around hey
this doesn't make sense why are you
doing this let's cut it or kill it and I
think there was a lot more aggressive
like pip culture for example at Facebook
compared to Pinterest right right how
about the technical stacks like when you
switch from Pinterest to Meta did you
have any issues learning Meta's very
custom stack I mean it's kind of
interesting because like on paper it was
quite similar like both as Android dev
both were using Java there was no Cotlin
really at the time. So Java there and it
was still using like Android tooling.
But I think one of the things that was
interesting is that Facebook was
operating at such a scale that they had
like workarounds for a lot of things.
They had their own customuilt system
called buck right that was relative.
That was very easy for me. And then a
lot of the ways of doing compilation for
Android at Facebook was different from
what I had learned which was exacerbated
or like made even more pronounced by the
fact that I was working on a hardware
team. So I joined a relatively unique
part of Facebook called Portal. And it
wasn't called portal all the time. It
was called building 8. It basically was
a forked version of Android along with
like 30 different custom Android apps
sitting on top of this custom operating
system. And so the building the build
system the tooling for that was actually
very very different not just for
Pinterest but also just for core of
Facebook. So that took some time like
probably it took me like four or five
months to understand how that even how
that worked. Got it. Yeah. And for for
people who don't know, Portal is the
standalone device that's a video calling
device that has a screen on it and it it
sits stationary. It's almost like a
Google Home. That that's the thing that
you're talking about, right? That's
right. I mean, initially you would have
like we had like literally like an
Android tablet because we didn't have
hardware when I first joined. But then
yeah, like eventually we had custom
hardware which had our own OS. We it was
like you call it flashing. You'd flash
the device with your own OS and on top
of that you would then put o over
optimize build of the 30 apps but then
you're not going to build all 30 apps.
That would take like literally three or
four hours. Then you would take the app
that you're working on like I was
working on the calling app. So I would
just build that app and then put that on
the device. So it's a very kind of
unique process even for Facebook which
took a long time to understand and
actually that was an opportunity like
you can talk about this later if you're
interested but I built out this like
debug tool which was just for people on
the portal because of how unique the
setup was and that actually led to a ton
of impact because I was able to
understand deeply how the workflow was
different compared to other internet
engineers and I was able to build
something to help with them. How many
engineers did that speed up? By the time
I built that tool, like portal had grown
dramatically. So I think by that point
like hundreds of engineers in the portal
org or adjacent orgs were using that
tool either every day or every week and
it was probably saving like hundreds of
hours of engineering time every month.
Yeah. So I mean to me that sounds like
IC6 impact or staff impact. So maybe we
can talk a little bit about career
growth at Meta. Did were you hired as a
IC5? So senior or Yeah. Okay. I was
hired as IC5. Yeah. Oh, so that was
probably a big part of moving as well.
Sounds like you got a promotion from
switching from Pinterest to to Meta.
Yep, that's right. Did you have to do
anything special to to get that that job
hop promo or you just did the interview
and that was what they proposed? Yeah,
that's what they proposed. I mean, I
think I I knew I had done the interviews
really well. Like I came out thinking
okay I felt really lucky or I felt
really good about okay I pretty much
nailed every problem and I came in in a
position of strength in a sense I I
already I already had I think a couple
pending offers at that point there's a
com and I had interned at Facebook I
like had worked at a respectable company
before which was Pinterest and I think
the market was hot for Android
developers so the combination of all of
that led to just like they wanted to
give me a compelling offer right you
went from senior or IC5 to to staff.
Yeah, maybe you can talk a little bit
about what you're working on. I
mentioned I'm work I work on a thing
called Portal which is a standalone
hardware video calling device and so
prior to Portal existing Facebook
already has a long history of doing
video calling primarily in the form of
doing it through messenger. So
Messenger, the Facebook Messenger app
already had a fairly mature ecosystem or
infrastructure around supporting
crossplatform video calls between
desktop and mobile, Android, iOS at
different with different codecs,
different qualities, different audio
video codecs, things like that. And so I
think a lot of the challenge was, hey,
the step zero is just effectively fork
off of Messenger and do our own thing
because we were just kind of an
experimental project. But then once
portal had launched and we had you know
hundreds of thousands of people who were
using portal every day then there was a
need to now kind of come back into the
normal infrastructure because like you
know obviously the RTC team like the
video calling infrastructure team at
messenger they were constantly making
improvements and it would always be a
challenge of how do we now stay up to
date and so the main project I I worked
on was moving the core infrastructure
back into what messenger had already
developed. So migrating the old infra to
the new infra while maintaining
compatibility with all the custom
features that portal had and adopting a
lot of the new features that the RTC
infra had enabled for us. So like kind
of navigating that at a product layer
and also the tech layer that was the
main project. I think one thing I tell
people is at the staff level you can
have one big project. I think some
people have that, but for me I think
having a portfolio approach worked out
really well. But that was like the main
thing that was really crossunctional and
frankly a lot of like bureaucracy where
it was managing people from the
messenger team, managing people from
portal leadership like getting everyone
in line, PMs and so I think the other
project that I mentioned earlier which
was a debug tool that was purely
engineering driven. I knew exactly who I
was building for which was me and other
engineers on the team. I think the
combination of those two led to a pretty
clear promo case when I was able to go
up for it. It sounds clearly like IC6
scope. You're you had to influence
across teams. Sounds like a pretty big
shared infrastructure initiative. I've
heard a lot of other people getting IC6
promos off of shared infra because that
central team probably made it so much
better in the interim when you were
branched away. So when you merge
together, it's almost like you unlocked
all of their engineers's work in this
new product surface. So were you
intentional about your growth to IC6?
Like was that something you you kept
talking to your manager about? You said,
"Hey, I want to get there or it just
happened naturally?" Yeah, I mean I
think the way you phrased the promotion
conversation matters a lot. So like I
think for the first year at Facebook, my
goal was really is let me make sure I do
well, right? Because I think a big
turnoff and I learned this when I was on
the other side as a manager later on,
but like if you have someone who just
joined the company and they're
immediately asking you, okay, like I
want to get promoted, can you help me?
Right? It's a big turnoff because even
especially for someone like me who
had felt some level of imposter syndrome
of like, hey, I came in at a fairly high
level. There's a lot of expectation. My
first priority for the first year was
really let me just nail it. let me make
sure that I'm exceeding expectation or
at least meeting expectation for E5 or
IC5 senior level before I think about
promotion. So after that year and I felt
like I now had developed some trust and
I landed some good work then I started
to have a really clear conversation with
a manager about what does it look like
to grow on the IC ladder? What does
management look like? Because even back
then I think there was some element of I
enjoyed talking to people. I enjoyed
mentoring people. So there was even
discussion back then on what would it
look like to be a manager. I think the
conclusion we came to and I think it was
the right one was let me first go up the
ladder as a IC like an individual
contributor and then maybe later on try
out the management path which is what
happened but it was a pretty like
thought through deliberate conversation.
You mentioned that there were two kind
of big efforts that helped you get
promoted. One of them was the the
tooling that you made which sounds like
that was a bottoms up initiative. You
knew it was bad. Yeah, you saw how many
people it could help and you just went
and built it. For the the other the
shared infrastructure initiative, did
you create that scope or was that
something that maybe your manager came
to you and said, "Hey, we got to do
this. Could you lead it?" How did you
get that opportunity? Yeah, that one was
more of like a it it was kind of obvious
that that had to be done by someone. And
I think I had been around the team long
enough and I had enough of a seniority
and relationship with the RTC team, like
the messenger team, to make it happen.
So it kind of felt like a natural fit of
okay, I can just step up and and do it
rather than it being something like I'm
going to create scope. It definitely was
like a obvious thing that both the RTC
team wanted and the portal team wanted.
It was a question of who could step up
and try and be the point person for this
initiative. Got it. And you were
naturally that person because you had
been delivering. You had all the
relationships and you'd been there for
long enough. Is that right? That's
right. Yeah. Yeah. I think it was kind
of very clear to everyone that if I
wanted it, I would probably be one of
the better people to take this on or
maybe the best person to take it on just
because I had been around long enough
and I had I knew the context of what
each team was trying to do and how to
make it kind of compatible, how to make
it work together. Okay. And so you you
talked a little bit about management and
I know you got the IC6 promo and then
later you switched to TLM and I was kind
of curious. I think a lot of people want
to make that same decision for their
their careers. So what was your
reasoning for wanting to switch? I mean
I do think genuinely the whole point of
like my company now is to try and help
people. So I think manage good managers
I think genuinely have a desire to help
people like they want to see people grow
and then I think as a byproduct of
helping people grow you also can
actually have a lot of impact managers
are generally quite senior and respected
at at most companies right so I that was
the initial motivation and again going
back to the idea of like I had a lot of
context I knew a lot of people so again
felt like a kind of a natural transition
in some sense like you have a growing
team and you want someone to give them
feedback and make sure they're working
high impact stuff okay, do you want to
become a manager? And so it was a very
it again it didn't feel forced at all.
It kind of felt like oh a very natural
like is something you've expressed
interest in in the past and also this
seems to be a natural fit here or the
organization needs it. Do you want to
try out management? Right. So let's say
someone's decided for themselves they
they definitely want to try management.
What are what are those concrete steps
that maybe you took for instance that
got you to actually become a manager?
Yeah, I think a couple things. One is
just ask ask yourself the question of do
you enjoy helping people? Do you enjoy
working with people? Like if you hate
one-on-one, do you dread the one-on-one
with your manager or one-on- ones with
other people? You're going to have a
really difficult time thriving as a
manager because a lot of your time is
going to be one-on- ones or even just
like ping like reacting to pings. And I
do think one of the hard parts about
management is that you become more of a
firefighter or you become more reactive
rather than proactive. Like you can't
guard your time as much. So the step one
is like are you willing to do you like
people enough and do you want to help
people enough that you're willing to
give up some of the autonomy or
flexibility that you might have had as
an engineer. If you've clarified that
with yourself and by the way you should
test that too like don't just like
intellectualize it. I think it's worth
actually having one-on- ones with people
and like start doing some of that motion
now even as I see if you think you might
want to become a manager. Another big
part of management honestly is having
opinions. You should have opinions not
only about the fe feedback of like what
quality of work people are doing on the
team and like how they could do better.
That's one part of the having opinions.
Another part about having opinions is
how should the team and organization
change based on different priorities of
the company or of of the or if you feel
like you haven't done that reflection or
if you don't want to do that reflection,
I actually don't think management is
again like it's not a good fit in the
sense that you wouldn't do well. I think
the best managers are the ones who come
in with a very strong point of view and
they're able to effectively bend the
organization to help them achieve what
they want. And so I think the
combination of those two like do you
number one enjoy helping people and like
testing out testing it out with one-on
ones and like meeting leading meetings
and things like that and then number two
do you care and do you want to be part
of like those kind of broader
organizational decisions around what the
team or what the org should do? I see.
And when you say have an opinion, okay,
I'm thinking from the IC perspective. So
for someone to kind of get a sense of if
they like that kind of work, it sounds
more of like the directional work and
the kind of like tech leadership work is
the best simulation of that. Is that
right? Yeah, that's right. I mean, I
think even a senior a very senior IC
effectively becomes part of the
expectation is that you should have very
clear opinions that you can articulate
and convince people of about what the
team should be doing for the next six
months or next one year. And if you feel
like you would really rather not have
those kind of negotiations with other
teams or other people about what the
team should do and you just want to be
more of like a I want to just execute
and write code and like feel productive
then I think management again is like
not a good fit. That was actually one of
the big challenges for me which is like
when I became a TLM. TLM in particular
is difficult because like you're kind of
straddling the line between doing IC
work and management work but I remember
feeling a lot of the time where at the
end of my day I was like what did I
actually achieve today? And really the
way I spent my time was in meetings
doing one-on ones trying to figure out
the road mapap for something. And if you
are approaching your job with the
mindset of let me just crank out code
and let me ship an experiment then you
might not be satisfied with how your day
or week is going if you don't do any of
that stuff. Was there anything that
surprised you when you switched to
management? I mean so I think in my case
in particular because I was a tech
league manager or was like a hybrid
role. I think that job was tough because
it's okay to be a TLM as a transitory
role where like you're deciding whether
you want to be a full-time manager like
a full-time M1 or M2 or you want to be a
full-time IC, but it's not a good place
to be in terms of long-term
sustainability because like you kind of
are not really clear about are you being
judged or evaluated on your IC work and
your ability to strip a lot of
interesting code or are you being
evaluated primarily on for people
leadership, right? And so that was
difficult for me. I I think I I was
surprised how taxing
that would be. Yeah. Um Yeah. And I
ended up switching teams like after
that. Oh, interesting. Yeah. I I I
switched to TLM too, kind of in a trans
transitory state to EM. And I asked a
lot of people before I switched, you
know, what they thought. I talked to
other TLMs and every single TLM I talked
to told me, hey, it's not a good idea to
to stay long-term. I have not heard one
person tell me that, hey, you should
become a TLM and it's a great idea in
the future because you kind of just
become this, you know, jack of all
trades, master of none. You're not
specialized and growing long-term in one
of the two paths. And also, it's like
unsustainable to try to do two jobs at
the same time at this point. Okay. You
got to staff TLM, you switched teams,
and after you switched teams, you you
ended up leaving Meta. You left Meta to
start your own company. I'm kind of
curious about the the story behind that.
What what made you want to leave Meta
and how did that happen? Yeah, I mean I
think like I mentioned before like I
think as tempered there's like in the
water somewhere there's like this kind
of like everyone thinks about starting a
company or talks about starting a
company and so I had definitely fallen
into that and it just in my mind
starting from like I would say 20 2016
like fairly early on I always had this
idea like okay I'm I want to do a
company just a question of when. Yeah.
And I finally felt like I was ready for
it at Meta for a couple of reasons.
Number one, probably the biggest reason
is I felt like I found a co-founder who
I wanted to try and explore an idea
with. I trusted them. I enjoyed working
with them and that was a huge unlock is
I I finally find someone found someone
who we have validated our relationship
and we like working with each other and
we have similar timelines. I think the
second thing was I felt like I had
reached a level in my career where I
felt satisfied or maybe the maybe
negative framing of it could be like I
felt like I had plateaued so it's okay.
made it and now like it's harder to see
a pathway to like a director or like
something very senior. So now is a good
time just to leave. And I I mean I also
felt like I mean you get well paid as an
engineer in general and I think I got
lucky through a combination of promotion
and just stop growth at Meta that I felt
like I didn't have to work for a few
years. So that was obviously important
in terms of optionality like I didn't
have to worry about finances. I could
cover my life for a couple years. And I
think the third and final thing was like
I call I had some signal of like I had
been doing tutorials about Android
actually at that point. I've been
publishing them on YouTube for a few
years starting in 2019. So I go like
that was another input. But there seems
to be something here. I enjoy teaching.
I enjoy working with developers. Can we
build something on it? Can we see what
happens? So the combination of all three
of those led me to feel confident about
leaving. you had already built up that
base of skills, money, a much stronger
foundation to start a company off of.
You know, co-founder is a big part of
the equation. Where did you find your
co-founder? Alex and I worked together
on Portal in 2017. When I first joined
the company, he was literally in the
same exact team with me. He ended up
switching actually relatively quickly,
but he we worked together pretty closely
for like a few months and then we stayed
in touch when he moved over to
Instagram. So, we probably met every
week in person at Facebook pre-COVID and
then once COVID happened, we started
talking like almost every other day.
Wow. Just like talking about different
ideas and different things we want to
try out together. When you ended up
quitting, did you already have something
built? Yeah, we had nothing built. I
mean, I think what we had done before we
quit was we had commit we had commitment
to each other that we would work on it
for at least, you know, 6 months or a
year. The second commitment we had to
each other was that we knew kind of the
broad domain area that we wanted to
operate in because a big part of that
was what we've been doing for maybe like
six months prior to us quitting is we
were just doing community building and
like research like during co we ran
these free webinars talking about
different elements of career growth and
those actually did quite well like I
think part of it was just like people
were really itching for interaction
social interaction at home and so we had
these webinars of like literally 800
people who joined it was a huge number
of people who just joined to hear us
talk about different elements of career
growth. And so we felt like, okay, we
are committed to this broad domain.
We're committed to working on it for a
certain amount of time. And we had this
ambition of like, let's figure out how
we can get funding or at least build
something once we quit. That was that
was the idea. I see. And so you guys
ended up applying to YC and getting
fundraising through that avenue. Is that
something you'd recommend to, let's say,
I'm a big tech employee thinking about
starting a company. Is YFC the best way
to get fundraising or is there more
behind that decision? It depends. Like
when you say start a company, it's kind
of like what we talked about earlier
with acquisition. Acquisition is such an
overloaded term. Start a company is also
a very overloaded term, right? You could
start a company which is like I'm going
to build utility apps on Android which
just get a million downloads and then
you make no money, right? Or you could
build small apps on on your phone which
make like 5K a month. That's a pretty
cool thing. Or you could just cover your
living expenses. or you could try and
make like a billion dollar company,
right? And so if you are in that latter
category where you have some ambition to
make a huge company, then I think yeah,
YC makes sense as like a funding
vehicle, I do think that it depends on
like your network. If you're a
first-time founder and you don't have
that much of a network, then YC is a
no-brainer. Like it's such an obvious
decision that you'll get credibility,
you that money, you get the
accountability of YC. But if you're a
repeat founder or if you already have a
network of other VCs like you already
know some of the top tier VC firm then
maybe you can make the argument that you
know YC is not worth it. So comparing
and so now you've been working on your
startup for some time now. What do you
see are the biggest differences between
the startup and that you're running for
yourself and and big tech? Oh there's so
many differences. I mean good and bad. I
mean I think one of the big changes
which is both good and bad is like I
think the structure accountability is
like you are in charge of it right
there's no boss there's no deadline me
Alex and we're a team of three so we're
still actually quite small we're three
full-time people and so we try to
manufacture urgency we try and
manufacture deadlines but unlike a
company like Facebook or Pinterest or
any other company really where almost
always you have like a cadence of a
quarterly release or some like big
launch coming up that you have that
going for you. You are in charge of
creating that structure for yourself
when you are doing a startup, right?
There's no manager, there's no boss,
there's no one looking out for you. So
that is both empowering and also very
scary like you have to work with urgency
otherwise you could spend five years you
know just like twiddling your thumbs and
that's not a good outcome. So that's one
big change. I also think that there's
kind of related there's a lot more
ambiguity what to build like even now I
I feel like it took us a while to get to
where Taro is now. Initially the idea
was just focused on let's build
something for developers and we thought
a dev tool could work like something in
I don't know reviewing code writing code
things like that but then we felt like
the community angle was more powerful so
we started going more into community and
that ended up going into courses and now
we have like this pretty robust course
platform along with some community
elements that product management
thinking is something that a lot of big
tech engineers in particular have no
idea how to do like talking to users
iterating on the feedback looking at
data you have to be willing to just dive
into a new area and like learn something
a lot more obviously when you're a two
person threeperson company compared to
when you have a worldass data scientist
or UXR person or you know whoever else
sitting next to you. Let's say you were
I guess giving advice to people who are
in big tech and they're they're kind of
thinking about it. At what point do you
think you would advise someone it could
make sense to start a company? I mean I
think this depends a lot on what you
define as success, right? So, here's the
thing. Like, you can have a very, very
amazing life if you just stick around
and you climb the ladder and you get to
like director or higher at Meta. Like,
that's an amazing amazing life and
you're in the top 0.1% of the people in
the world. But I think if you want to
have a lot more control and autonomy
over what you do and what you build, and
you also want an outlier outcome,
outlier meaning like you want to have a
small small chance of a huge outcome.
It's actually very hard to have that
happen in a big tech company because
like a big tech company, I mean, I could
be proven wrong, but I don't think Meta
is going to like 5x in value in the next
5 years, right? It might double, which
would be amazing, but it's probably not
going to 5x or 10x. And so, if you want
to have something which is 10xing in
value, then I think that could be like a
time. So, like I would say like when you
have the stability, this foundation
laid, that's how I think about it. like
you've worked in big tech, you have the
credibility, you have the finances. Now,
now you can go for a bigger swing, then
that could be one input into doing a
startup. And the other thing is what we
mentioned before, which is like you have
to really get along with your
co-founder. It's like a marriage. And so
if you find someone who you really feel
like you get along with and critically
the timing works out because that's the
other thing I noticed is that sometimes
people have the their dream co-founder
in mind and they're kind of just waiting
and they're never on the same timeline
where it's like oh one person is waiting
for a bonus or a vesting period. So
they're going to wait for six more
months and the other person when they
wait six more months they have a kid and
now oh now my kid is like I'm going to
wait until they're in daycare. they wait
two more years or whatever and then the
other person in two more years they're
now like oh I have to get married. It's
like having the alignment on the
timeline and like your commitment to how
long you want to do the startup that is
you dare to find as well. Yeah. I had a
I had a friend who was at Meta and then
he left to go do his own company and I
asked him his motive and he said he felt
like he would regret if he looked back
on his life and he had did that big tech
trajectory the whole time. he would just
regret that he didn't have a a story
worth telling. So yeah, there's so many
different ways to look at it. I think
the last things I want to ask a little
bit about I guess reflecting over
everything looking back on all the
different legs you had a little bit of
startup big tech a few legs of big tech
and now you're back in startup but as a
founder rather than engineer what period
of your career did you feel like you had
the most skill growth or or career
growth? I would say when I found that
really amazing mentor at Pinterest, that
was one period of dramatic growth where
I was like pair programming and finding
this person and like it's there are a
lot of things you learn by osmosis that
you don't get taught but just like
seeing how he operated and made this
separate mini app that we talked about
that was like eye opening for me like
you are empowered to change your
environment and do things that was
powerful I think at Meta when I started
or Facebook before when I was there when
I was actually meeting a team and doing
this migration that was powerful and
along with that the um debug tool, this
like tooling change I made, that was the
first time I felt like I built
something, especially in the big tech
environment where like I was creating
value. Like I felt like I was creating
value for the first time, which is kind
of odd to say, but I felt like a lot of
the other things I had done, I felt like
a worker be, right? You know, like I
felt like, okay, this is like something
which is being sent up, sent down from
above. I'm going to be like a good
Android developer or I'm going to be a
good you know recommendation system
engineer and just like do it and for the
first time I felt like I an idea that I
had come up with like it was my baby and
I was able to actually put out in the
world and people were willing to adopt
it like that was I think a crazy eye
openener again for me which probably led
to like why I felt confident also doing
a startup and maybe the third thing I
would say which is not really maybe
relevant to a big tech audience but I
felt like the two months or three months
of YC when we were doing like the actual
YC period where you had a group check-in
every week and you talk to people every
week about what you've done. That was
also very intense. But I learned a lot
in that process just cuz like if you
don't perform like you're kind of being
shamed and like you have this intense
pressure to like get things done. And
what about looking back? I think this is
something people are always interested
in is if you if you look at everything,
is there anything that you regret or
that other people could learn from where
you think, man, I wish I changed that?
And if so, what what would it be? That's
a good question. I feel like the startup
I joined in 2014, I think that I don't
necessarily regret it because I think I
learned a lot. I have a good story to
tell from it. But if I'm if I'm looking
back at the reason I did it, honestly,
I'm not sure if it was the best decision
because a lot of it was I maybe somewhat
ego-driven of like I don't want to be
one of many people in big tech. I want
to do the special thing. I want to go do
this thing which is unique to me. And it
was unique to me. So that was true. Like
I I think I felt special doing it. But
at the same time, I feel like I don't
know if I had enough maturity as an
engineer to really handle this scenario.
like I I did I think flounder or
struggle a bit both at the startup and
also when I joined Pinterest. So I think
maybe going into a more structured
environment would have maybe been a
better bet for me in terms of my
maturation as an engineer. So that's the
one that comes to mind. But I think in
general I I would say I don't really
have that many regrets. Like I just feel
again and again in my career I've been
so lucky. Like it may that's weird to
say or think about but like there have
been so many jobs where I've been
rejected for which honestly if I had
gotten the offer I would have taken it
and that company completely exploded
like a year later. Which one? Um, and
also even in the VC world, like there
were a couple VC firms that strung us
along so badly with Taro and they were
like, "Oh, we'll invest in you at this
valuation. We'll give you this amount of
money." And it didn't work out. Like we
we effectively got rejected and then I
look back at like how Taro has
progressed and what we've been able to
do and what pressure we would have felt
with those VC firms on our cap table.
And again, I just feel so lucky. Like I
feel like in this weird way I have
failed my way into success. Like I just
gotten so lucky again and again with um
getting or not getting opportunities and
that's led me to where I am today.
Right. You know when people see a career
like yours, they're going to say
something like it was luck. I guess my
question to you is what portion of your
career growth do you think was luck? Oh,
I think a lot of it was luck. I think I
think yeah super lucky like um with the
opportunities and the people I came
across I will say like you can
manufacture luck in the sense of being
curious about the people and the
opportunities around you. I think a lot
of the ways I would been able to find my
co-founder, find that startup in 2014,
get the opportunities at Facebook is I
think one thing I do a relatively good
job of is keeping in touch with people.
Like I try and just be friendly with,
oh, you know, will you take that class
together? What do what have you been up
to? What do you like about your new job?
Or, you know, let me know if I can help
out with this particular project that
you're working on. Right? I I feel like
that's something I've always enjoyed
doing. And it turned out that that has
career value as well because you're able
to get exposure to projects, people,
ideas that you wouldn't know otherwise.
Even like the things that we talked
about in this conversation a couple
times, like that debug tool I built at
Meta came from me talking to a bunch of
people and just like understanding their
workflow. Me doing a lot of the job hops
in my career have come from just again
being kind of in the know on what are
the people doing that I respect. And so
I think that can be a repeatable
algorithm or repeatable process that's
not dependent on luck. I guess just
change your approach to networking I
guess or or like talking to people and
that's a really good way to manufacture
luck. And I think actually, you know,
one thing that's just like maybe come
present day and I think both me and you
are pretty active on social media,
right? Like we post a lot, maybe too
much. And so I feel like part of it is
of course like just genuine wanting to
put out some value in the world
hopefully. But also part of it is like
that's a way to create luck, right? Like
you are putting out content and people
can see it and resonate with it, help
them, and then they'll think of you when
it comes to career growth. They'll think
of you for a certain opportunity. And so
that's a good example of yeah, it's kind
of blocked because you don't know who's
going to see your post, but at the same
time that was a very deliberate thing
and we probably spend many hours per
week or per month thinking about what
that will look like and how we can help
people. Yeah. No, definitely agree. And
I I've heard some people call this, you
know, maximizing your luck surface area.
And I think yeah, social media is one
thing too, but even just wherever you
are, maybe like internally at your
company, I feel like writing or putting
things out or reaching out to people,
that visibility just gets you more
opportunities. Probably part of the
reason why you got the project that got
you to staff, the one where you were
helping with the big shared
infrastructure initiative, you were you
had relationships and credibility
already because of you talking to
people. you putting out writing that
says, "Hey, I'm the person leading this
initiative and hey, it was successful."
That's essentially giving people reason
to trust you and give you future
opportunities, which increases your
luck. I think one thing you said was
about how you're good at, I guess, like
reaching out to people and it sounded
like what you were doing was really
natural and I think when people talk
about networking, it feels a little bit
more manufactured. So, do you have any
tip on how to quote unquote network with
with people? Yeah, actually that's
that's a really good call out. Like I I
actually hesitated to use the word
networking because I never really
thought of it as networking for what
I've been doing for most of my career. I
think the things that I think about when
I do it is one genuine curiosity. Like I
genuinely am interested in what you're
doing. How are you doing? Like how are
you enjoying it or not enjoying whatever
you're up to? That's part of it. And the
second thing is being thoughtful about
what are you sharing? I do think that
one of the best ways to develop a
relationship with someone is not just by
asking a ton of questions or like asking
for mentorship. A really good way to
develop a relationship is say, "Hey,
here's something I've worked on which
might be interesting to you." The best
way to get inbound is like to show off.
Not maybe not show off is not the right
word, but like to showcase um what
you've been up to and like here's why
you have a unique insight or a unique
project that turns out to be a really
interesting way or a really compelling
way for people to like you create
gravity. Like you gra people gravitate
toward you because they want to get your
opinion on things too. So it's like a
two-way street. And if it's always if it
feels like you're the one always asking
and it's not reciprocated, then it could
just be that person is not interested in
you and that's time. But it could also
be, hey, could you make yourself more
interesting? And that that actually
being a really good way to network.
Yeah. Yeah. I remember when I was a new
grad, people would say networking so
important. And I thought, okay, so I'm
supposed to, I guess, reach out to
people and connect to them and this and
it felt really artificial. And so I
never really did it. And then more
recently, I have all these these side
things that, you know, I'm writing
content or I'm I'm building like a
keyboard on the side, this little
project. And I've noticed that it has
made conversations so much more natural
because there's this unusual interesting
side mission that I'm doing that people
kind of checking in on. Also similarly
like you have so much stuff too that
you're working on that even when I just
meet you we could probably talk for
hours just going over the stuff that I'm
curious about that you're working on. So
I guess the the last thing that I'd like
to go over and this is something that I
ask everyone is if you were to go back
to yourself at the end of college you're
right about to enter the industry and
you're going to give yourself some
advice knowing everything that you know
today. What is something that you tell
yourself at the beginning of your career
that you think would make the biggest
difference? I think the thing I wish I
realized way way earlier in my career is
that there are no gatekeepers. Like you
don't need permission from anyone when
it comes to learning a technology or
trying out something new. Like I think
in school like I I did well in like high
school. I did fairly well in college.
Like I I think I was able to do that
because I was very methodical and stious
with whatever I was given. But I don't
think I was as creative or like as
exploratory as I could have been. Like
for example like your project of
building out a keyboard. That's so cool.
Like you didn't need permission. You
didn't no one told to do that. You just
did it. And those are the things that I
think are the most interesting. Even
okay, build out a mobile app for fun or
like I had this recent project now where
I'm building out some extensions for a
app launcher on my Mac. Like it's like
random things. Like I think if I had
learned earlier that you are empowered
and you should feel like this desire to
do something unique based off of what
you care about rather than just doing
what everyone else around you is doing
or what the instructor or the manager is
telling you to do. That is how you get
an outlier outcome. And I wish I had
tried harder to cultivate more creative
interests, I would say, earlier on or at
least allocated time to those creative
interests in a much more deliberate way
than what I did for most of my career.
So, and it sounds like in the second
half of your career, you started to take
more of that initiative and kind of just
will your way into creating the tools or
this new company that you've been
working on. And so, it sounds like
that's made a big difference. Is that
right? And you wish you had done that
sooner. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, I feel like
I got there eventually with like, okay,
I made tutorials on YouTube and I I
remember feeling so much joy when people
started commenting on my YouTube
tutorials like, "Oh, this is such a
magical, helpful tutorial. Thank you for
making it." I love that feeling. I
published Android apps. I um started
doing these like webinars with 800
people. Like it felt like someone lift
off the blindfolds and like you can do
anything. Like you're not going to be
ready to go start a company. you're not
going to be ready to go like publish an
app. You're not going to be ready to go
teach people. Just do it now. And I
think I wasn't this like wait and let me
get better, let me get smarter, let me I
don't know. So that's something about
like just me being way more passive
early on in my career. And until at some
point I'm like, hey, I'm old enough.
I've I've done enough. I like got a job
already. Like what am I waiting for? Let
me just go do it. I wish I had adopted
that mindset way early. Even in like
middle school or high school, I think
it's not too early. But you can just
start having that same mindset of
creative expression or just like
pursuing things that you care about way
earlier way earlier on in life. Right.
So it's kind of like the um the main
character energy versus the NPC energy.
Is that right? Yeah, I like that. Yeah.
I mean it you don't have to be a main
character in every domain of your life.
Those kind of people might be kind of
annoying to to be with like in certain
domains. Like I think it's good to try
and be the main character in like
certain parts of your life at least, you
know, like for things that you care
about or things where you have a unique
take. I like that. That's maybe a Yeah,
don't be the NPC. Just be the main
character. Awesome. Well, that's Yeah,
that's everything. Thanks so much for
sharing all this. I think there's so
much gold in here for the audience. I
really appreciate it. And at this point,
if you want to plug anything, yeah,
now's the time to do it. So anything you
want to mention to for the audience? I
mean we touched on it for a bit but like
I mean I am working for the past two and
a half years on this company called
Taro. It is born out of my own
experience in the tech industry like how
do I grow my career? How do I figure out
how to feel more confident, productive,
get paid more money? And so if people
are interested in that kind of stuff
they want to get feedback or advice from
really smart people who I respect. Like
I've been working on that every day for
the past two and a half years and I'm
I'm really proud of kind of the
knowledge that we've been able to
accumulate. So people can check that out
jointaro.com or you know just follow me
or connect with me on LinkedIn. I'm
happy to do whatever I can to help
people. I'll put all the links to
Rahul's uh YouTube to Taro to his
LinkedIn as well. So you can see that in
the show notes. Thanks for for for
coming, Rahul. Yeah, thanks for having
me. This was super fun. Hey everyone,
Ryan here. Thanks for listening. I hope
you enjoyed the conversation with Rahul.
I really appreciated how transparent he
was throughout the entire conversation.
So, I hope that it was really helpful.
You can take a look in the show notes. I
left a bunch of links to him if you want
to get more from Rahul. And if you have
any feedback about the show, anything
that you liked or that you disliked, I'd
love to hear it. You can leave comments
on YouTube. That's where I've been
checking for feedback. I'll read every
comment that I get. Also, if you have
any requests for future guests or maybe
questions that you wish I would have
asked, would also love to hear that as
well. Thanks again for listening and I
hope to see you in a future